chartiq.com 2018-10-28

# Privacy Policy | ChartIQ

Last updated May 24, 2018.

We at ChartIQ, Inc. are committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to our websites (www.chartiq.com, www.info.chartiq.com, and www.blog.chartiq.com). This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing, and usage practices. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, and correction of your personal information. If you do not agree with the data practices described in this Privacy Policy, you should not use any of our websites.

We periodically update this Privacy Policy as our data collection, processing, and usage practices change. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our treatment of the information you provide us, please contact us.

Email: [info@chartiq.com](mailto:info@chartiq.com) with the subject line “Privacy Policy.

Mail:  ChartIQ, Inc.

        609 East Market Street

        Suite #111

        Charlottesville, VA 22902

### How we Collect Information

**When you visit our websites**

You are free to explore our websites without providing any Personal Information about yourself. When you visit our websites, we request that you provide Personal Information about yourself, and we collect Navigational Information. 

**“Personal Information”**

This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, job title, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on our websites, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.

Personal Information also includes Navigational Information information can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Navigational information refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit, and pages viewed. Please see the “Navigation Information” section below.

**Log files**

When you use our services or view content provided by us, we automatically collect information about your computer hardware and software. This information can include your IP address, browser type, domain names, internet service provider (ISP), the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, clickstream data, access times, and referring website addresses. This information is used by ChartIQ, Inc. to provide general statistics regarding use of our ChartIQ websites. For these purposes, we do link this automatically-collected data to Personal Information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.

**Information we collect from third parties**

From time to time, we may receive Personal Information about you from third party sources including partners with which we offer co-branded services or engage in joint marketing activities and publicly available sources such as social media websites.

**Information about children**

Our websites are not intended for or targeted at children under 16, and we do not knowingly or intentionally collect information about children under 16. If you believe that we have collected information about a child under 16, please contact us at info@chartiq.com, so that we may delete the information.

### How we use the information we collect

**Compliance with our Privacy Policy**

We use the information we collect only in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Customers are obligated through our agreements with them to comply with this Privacy Policy.

**We never sell Personal Information**

We will never sell your Personal Information to any third party. 

**Use of Personal Information**

In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we may use your Personal Information to:

  * improve your browsing experience by personalizing our websites;
  * send information or ChartIQ, Inc. content to you which we think may be of interest to you by    post, email, or other means and send you marketing communications relating to our business;
  * promote use of our products to you and share promotional and information content with you in accordance with your communication preferences;
  * privately or publicly disclose statistical information about our users – will not be used to identify any individual user;
  * send information to you regarding changes to our Privacy Policy or other legal agreements;
  * meet legal requirements.

We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, we do not transfer your Personal Information to the third party.

We use the information collected through our sales onboarding process by our customers for the following purposes:

  * to provide the Subscription Service (which may include the detection, prevention, and resolution of security and technical issues);
  * to respond to customer support requests; and
  * otherwise to fulfill the obligations under the ChartIQ, Inc. Terms of Service. 

**Legal basis for processing Personal Information (EEA visitors only)**

If you are a visitor/customer located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), ChartIQ, Inc. in Charlottesville, VA is the data controller of your personal information and can be contacted at info@chartiq.com. 

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

**Use of Navigational Information**

We use Navigational Information to operate and improve our websites. We may also use Navigational Information alone or in combination with Personal Information to provide you with personalized information about ChartIQ, Inc. 

**Customer testimonials and comments**

We post customer testimonials and comments on our websites, which may contain Personal Information. We obtain each customer’s consent via email, phone, or verbally prior to posting the customer or partner’s name and testimonial.

**Security of your Personal Information**

We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. All Personal Information is protected using appropriate physical, technical, and organizational measures.

**Social Media Features**

Our websites include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our sites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the companies providing them.

**External websites**

Our websites provide links to other websites. We do not control and are not responsible for, the content or practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to any privacy and other policies they may have.

**Retention of Personal Information**

How long we keep the information we collect about you depends on the type of information as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible. 

We retain Personal Information that you provide to us where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, as long as is required in order to contact you about our products or our other services, or as needed to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Information, we securely delete the information or anonymize it or, if this is not possible, then we will securely store your Personal Information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. We will delete this information from the servers at an earlier date if you so request, as described in “To Unsubscribe from Our Communications” below.

If you have elected to receive marketing communications from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest in our content, products, or services, such as when you last opened an email from us. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date such information was created. 

### How We Share Information We Collect

**Service providers**

We employ other companies and people to provide services to visitors to our websites and our customers and may need to share your information with them to provide information, products or services to you. Examples may include removing repetitive information from prospect lists, analyzing data or performing statistical analysis, providing marketing assistance, supplementing the information you provide us in order to provide you with better service, and providing customer service or support. In all cases where we share your information with such agents, we explicitly require the agent to acknowledge and adhere to our privacy and customer data handling policies.

**ChartIQ, Inc. partners**

In addition, we may share data with trusted partners to contact you based on your request to receive such communications, help us perform statistical analysis, or provide customer support. Such third parties are prohibited from using your Personal Information except for these purposes, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

We partner with trusted third parties to provide you with co-marketing content that we think may be relevant to you. When you engage with these co-marketing partners, we will tell you who we are sharing data with, and provide a link to the co-marketing partner’s privacy policy so you can learn more about how to opt-out of the partner’s communications. These co-marketing partners are required to adhere to our privacy and data protection policies.

**Corporate events**

If we (or our assets) are acquired by another company, whether by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or otherwise, that company would receive all information gathered by ChartIQ, Inc. on our websites and the customer database. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your Personal Information, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

**Compelled disclosure**

We reserve the right to use or disclose your Personal Information if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a law, court order, or legal process.

### International Transfer of Information

**International transfer within ChartIQ entities**

To facilitate our global operations, we transfer information to either United Kingdom, Cyprus, or the United States and allow access to that information from countries in which ChartIQ Inc. has operations for the purposes described in this policy.

This Privacy Policy shall apply even if we transfer Personal Information to other countries. We have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your Personal Information will remain protected.

We also may transfer your information to third parties who provide services to ChartIQ that are based in other countries who may not have equivalent privacy and data protection laws to the country in which you reside. 

### Cookies and Similar Technologies

**Cookies**

ChartIQ, Inc. and its partners use cookies or similar technologies (such as web beacons) to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

**Advertising**

We partner with third-party ad networks to display ads on other sites. Our ad network partners use cookies and web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: [http://preferences.truste.com/](http://preferences.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union, by clicking here: [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Third-party tracking technologies**

The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is not covered by our Privacy Policy. 

### Reviewing, Correcting and Removing Your Personal Information

**You have the following data protection rights:**

  * You can request access, correction, updates, or deletion of your personal information at any time.
  * You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information.
  * If we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. Contact details for data protection authorities in the EEA, Switzerland, and certain non-European countries (including the US and Canada) are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).)

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at info@chartiq.com or by mail to ChartIQ, Inc., 609 East Market Street, Suite #111, Charlottesville, VA 22902 USA. We will respond to your request to change, correct, or delete your information within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

**To unsubscribe from our communications**

You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our e-mails, updating your communication preferences, or by sending us email us at info@chartiq.com or postal mail to ChartIQ, Inc., 609 East Market Street, Suite #111, Charlottesville, VA 22902 USA. Customers cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with us.

**To unsubscribe from our customer and partner communications**

Our customers are solely responsible for their own marketing emails and other communications; we cannot unsubscribe you from their communications. You can unsubscribe from our customers’ marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of their emails, or by contacting them directly.

**Contact**

ChartIQ, Inc.

609 East Market Street

Suite #111

Charlottesville, VA 22902
